<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>SLRB - data</title><link href="https://slrb.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://slrb.net/feeds/data.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://slrb.net/</id><updated>2016-09-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>BALDEY Database of Auditory Lexical Decisions</title><link href="https://slrb.net/BALDEY.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:slrb.net,2016-09-09:/BALDEY.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Data on auditory lexical decisions to over 5,000 spoken content words and pseudowords by 20 native speakers of Dutch.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://hdl.handle.net/1839/00-0000-0000-0020-449F-1"&gt;BALDEY Database of Auditory Lexical Decisions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description: In an auditory lexical decision experiment, 5,541 spoken content words and pseudo-words were presented to 20 native speakers of Dutch. The words vary in phonological makeup and in number of syllables and stress pattern, and are further representative of the native Dutch vocabulary in that most are morphologically complex, comprising two stems or one stem plus derivational and inflectional suffixes, with inflections representing both regular and irregular paradigms; the pseudo-words were matched in these respects to the real words. The BALDEY data file includes response times and accuracy rates, with for each item morphological information plus phonological and acoustic information derived from automatic phonemic segmentation of the stimuli. Two initial analyses illustrate how this data set can be used. First, we discuss several measures of the point at which a word has no further neighbors, and compare the degree to which each measure predicts our lexical decision response outcomes. Second, we investigate how well four different measures of frequency of occurrence (from written corpora, spoken corpora, subtitles and frequency ratings by 70 participants) predict the same outcomes. These analyses motivate general conclusions about the auditory lexical decision task. The (publicly available) BALDEY database lends itself to many further analyses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: Miriam Ernestus and Anne Cutler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type: acoustic database, behavioural perception database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Languages: Dutch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citation: Ernestus, M., &amp;amp; Cutler, A. (2015). BALDEY: A database of auditory lexical decisions. Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology, 68(8), 1469-1488. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;License: N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080%2F17470218.2014.984730"&gt;present&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit tests: N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publications: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1080%2F17470218.2014.984730"&gt;Ernestus &amp;amp; Cutler (2015)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="data"></category><category term="auditory-lexical-decision"></category><category term="morphological-complexity"></category><category term="frequency"></category><category term="phonological-neighbors"></category><category term="Dutch"></category><category term="database"></category></entry><entry><title>Spanish Confusions Corpus</title><link href="https://slrb.net/spanish-confusions-corpus.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:slrb.net,2014-01-01:/spanish-confusions-corpus.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A large-scale corpus of noise-induced robust misperceptions in Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://laslab.org/resources/confusions/"&gt;Spanish Confusions Corpus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: Máté Attila Tóth, María Luisa García Lecumberri, Yan Tang, and Martin Cooke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type: behavioral-data, audio-data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Languages: Spanish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citation: Tóth, M. A., Lecumberri, M. L. G., Tang, Y., &amp;amp; Cooke, M. (2015). A corpus of noise-induced word misperceptions for Spanish. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 137, EL184&lt;/em&gt;; doi: &lt;a href="10.1121/1.4905877"&gt;10.1121/1.4905877&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;License: N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: &lt;a href="http://laslab.org/resources/confusions/"&gt;present&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit tests: N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publications: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1121/1.4905877"&gt;Tóth et al. (2015)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="data"></category><category term="misperceptions"></category><category term="errors"></category><category term="word-recognition"></category><category term="noise"></category><category term="Spanish"></category></entry><entry><title>British Lexicon Project</title><link href="https://slrb.net/BLP.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>admin</name></author><id>tag:slrb.net,2012-01-01:/BLP.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Database of lexical decision times for approximately 14,000 English words and nonwords responded to by British participants.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://crr.ugent.be/blp"&gt;British Lexicon Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description: We present a new database of lexical decision times for English words and nonwords, for which two groups of British participants each responded to 14,365 monosyllabic and disyllabic words and the same number of nonwords for a total duration of 16 h (divided over multiple sessions). This database, called the British Lexicon Project (BLP), fills an important gap between the Dutch Lexicon Project (DLP; Keuleers, Diependaele, &amp;amp; Brysbaert, Frontiers in Language Sciences. Psychology, 1, 174, 2010) and the English Lexicon Project (ELP; Balota et al., 2007), because it applies the repeated measures design of the DLP to the English language. The high correlation between the BLP and ELP data indicates that a high percentage of variance in lexical decision data sets is systematic variance, rather than noise, and that the results of megastudies are rather robust with respect to the selection and presentation of the stimuli. Because of its design, the BLP makes the same analyses possible as the DLP, offering researchers with a new interesting data set of word-processing times for mixed effects analyses and mathematical modeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author: Emmanuel Keuleers, Paula Lacey, Kathleen Rastle, and Marc Brysbaert &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type: text database, digital lexicon, behavioral perception database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Languages: English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citation: Keuleers, E., Lacey, P., Rastle, K., &amp;amp; Brysbaert, M. (2012). The British Lexicon Project: Lexical decision data for 28,730 monosyllabic and disyllabic English words. Behavior Research Methods 44, 287–304.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;License: N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-011-0118-4"&gt;present&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit tests: N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publications: &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-011-0118-4"&gt;Keuleers et al. (2012)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="data"></category><category term="text-database"></category><category term="lexicon"></category><category term="behavioural-perception"></category><category term="visual-word-recognition"></category><category term="lexical-decision"></category><category term="megastudy"></category><category term="virtual-experiment"></category><category term="English"></category></entry></feed>